LIAM PEWTON FERRER

Junior Software Developer

Contact: +353 89 958 9703; liampewton99@gmail.com; Dublin

Hyperlinks: GITHUB; LINKEDIN

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY:

Junior software developer studying a Professional Diploma in Full Stack Software Development at Code Institute-UCD. 5 years of experience in Customer Service and tourism in different cities of Europe, where I learnt to work easily with a team or on my own and to keep cool under pressure.

Looking for a developer role in which I can grow, learn and expand my knowledge. Though I find front-end languages more intuitive, though I also have experience in backend languages.

EDUCATION

09/2022 – 08/2023 Professional Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute (CI-UCD) – University Accredited by the University

of West Scotland and UCD

University of Barcelona (UB)

09/2015 - 06/2017 Baccalaureate: Scientific

Bosc de la Coma – Olot (Spain)

TECHNICAL SKILLSET:

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Version Control: Git, Github, Heroku

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

1. Ireland's National Parks: Website on Ireland's National Parks for locals or for tourists.

Technologies used: HTML and CSS.

Github: https://github.com/lpewton/ireland-national-parks

2. Blackjack 21: Website that displays a game of Blackjack 21.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS and JavaScript. **Github:** https://github.com/lpewton/blackjack-21

3. **Film Picker:** Back-end app that contains a film database and allows users to add films, alter the list or get random suggestions.

Technologies used: Python.

Heroku: https://film-picker-lpewton.herokuapp.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/2022 – Now Customer Service
Premium Travel Club – Dublin

- Booking reservations for the customers on Navision (Booking system)
- Responsible for online payments
- Providing general information and troubleshooting customer issues
- Updating the personal details on customer's files

- Organising table distribution through a program
- Administering the correct receipts for customers
- Logging in reservations to the system

01/2021 - 10/2022 -- Covid Lockdown and relocation to Ireland ------

10/2019 - 12/2020 Customer Service
Sagrada Familia Cathedral – Barcelona

- Responsible for generating and printing out tickets for tourists
- Giving tours through the cathedral
- Organizing and making sure the group tours were in their time slot
- Selling tickets for the appropriate time slots

LANGUAGES

Native English (Spoken and written) Native Spanish (Spoken and written) Native Catalan (Spoken and written)